A Guide to the Charles Olson Research Collection 1969.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series I: Works, undated, 1927-1969
  - F. Essays
    - L-M (Box 32)
      - My Favorite Forgotten Book. Prose No. 13. Typescript/Carbon copy. 8p., May 12, 1946. (Box 32, Folder 1634)
      - My poor nerves are so exacerbated. Prose No. 148. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1965-1968. (Box 32, Folder 1635)
      - The Mystery of What Happens When It Happens. Prose No. 201. Manuscript/Carbon copy. 8p., ca. 1948. (Box 32, Folder 1636)
      - The Mystery of What Happens When It Happens. Prose No. 202. Typescript. 6p., ca. 1948-1949. (Box 32, Folder 1637)
      - The Mystery of What Happens When It Happens. Prose No. 28. Typescript. 21p., December 1948-January 1950. (Box 32, Folder 1638)
      - "Myth and logos..." Prose No. 44. Photocopy of typescript. 6p., ca. 1952-1956. (Box 32, Folder 1639)
      - Mythography and Geometry. Prose No. 214. Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1949. (Box 32, Folder 1640)
    - N-O (Box 33)
      - Nakedness, or the nude outside art. Prose No. 118. Photocopy. 1p., ca. June 14, 1959. (Box 33, Folder 1641)
      - Names; and place. Prose No. 142. Manuscript. 1 notepad., January 27, 1964. (Box 33:1642)
      - The narrow and the wide. Prose No. 249. Typescript. 1p., 1953. (Box 33:1643)
      - Natchez Trace: Seven Plays. Prose No. 6. Manuscript/Typescript. 8p., ca. 1954. (Box 33:1644)
      - The Necessary Propositions. Prose No. 238. Typescript. 5p., ca. May 1952. (Box 33:1645)
      - The New Empire. Prose No. 270. Typescript. 4p., 1954. (Box 33:1646)
      - New sciences of man. Prose No. 248. Typescript. 2p., 1953. (Box 33:1647)
      - The New Sciences of Man, Session No. 8. Prose No. 260. Typescript/Photocopy. 15p., February 1953. (Box 33:1648)
      - The New Sciences of Man, Session No. 10. Prose No. 262. Typescript. 6p., March 1953. (Box 33:1649)
      - The New Sciences of Man, The cave's recesses... Prose No. 263. Manuscript. 8p., March 1953. (Box 33:1650)
      - New sense from a flood of suddenly increased young persons... Prose No. 155. Photocopy of manuscript. 6p., December 12, 1965. (Box 33:1651)
      - A New Short Ars Poetica, a litle boke. Prose No. 89. Typescript. 3p., ca. 1955-1956. (Box 33:1652)
      - The Nineteenth of April. Prose No. 7. Typescript. 4p., ca. 1960-1962. (Box 33:1653)
      - No slow and flow the way in each instant. Prose No. 312. Manuscript/Typescript. 4p., November 7, 1967. (Box 33:1654)
      - Not Down. Prose No. 140. Typescript. 1p., January 4, 1964. (Box 33:1655)
      - A Note for Anyone Able to. Prose No. 298. Manuscript. 1p., ca. January - February 1964. (Box 33:1656)
      - Note on Havelock's Preface to Plato. Prose No. 129. Typescript. 2p., 1963. (Box 33:1657)
      - Note on type-face. Prose No. 33. Typescript. 1p. 4p. of photocopies from "Dance of India" attached., ca. 1950. (Box 33:1658)
      - Notes for a book on the West. Prose No. 194. Typescript. 1p., November 20, 1946. (Box 33:1659)
      - Notes for a lecture on Corrado Cagli and the 4th Dimension. Prose No. 31. Typescript. 5p., ca. December 15, 1949. (Box 33:1660)
      - Notes for a response to "A Letter From Italy." Prose No. 203. Manuscript/Typescript/Carbon copy. 15p., ca. 1948. (Box 33:1661)
      - Notes for the Proposition: Man is Prospective. Prose No. 25. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 27p., ca. 1948. (Box 33:1662)
      - Notes from reading Frobenius and Fox. Prose No. 309. Manuscript. 2p., December 12, 1965. (Box 33:1663)
      - Notes made April 4th. Prose No. 145. Typescript. 3p., ca. 1964-1965. (Box 33:1664)
      - Notes on the Source of the Imagination. Prose No. 94. Manuscript/Typescript. 4p., August 21, 1955. (Box 33:1665)
      - "Nudae Quantitates": A Character to Verse Itself. Prose No. 283. Typescript. 5p., December 1956. (Box 33:1666)
      - Of Charles Olson. Prose No. 240. Carbon copy. 2p., November 4, 1952. (Box 33:1667)
      - On receiving a book of poems. Prose No. 66. Typescript. 2p., March 24, 1953. (Box 33:1668)
      - Once you know your own name... Prose No. 307. Manuscript. 9p., 1965. (Box 33:1669)
      - Only a true crusade... Prose No. 153. Photocopy of manuscript. 4p., November 20, 1965. (Box 33:1670)
      - An Original New and Audaciously Aboriginal, Erratic Operatic, Historico-plagiaristic, Pre-patriotic Extravaganza... Prose No. 167. Typescript. 43p., ca. 1930. (Box 33:1671)
      - Origo. Prose No. 18. Typescript/Carbon copy. 62p., April 1947. (Box 33:1672)
      - Our loves are an expression of our fate... Prose No. 222. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1950. (Box 33:1673)
      - Outline for new sciences of man. Prose No. 247. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., February 1953. (Box 33:1674)
      - An Outline of a Projected Poem called West. Prose No. 192. Typescript. 8p., ca. 1946. (Box 33:1675)
      - Outside, Inside: Notes on Narrative, Provoked by Mr. Creeley's Stories. Prose No. 226. Typescript. 3p., October 1950. (Box 33:1676)
    - P-Q
      - Pacific Northwest Writer's Conference lecture notes. Typescript., July-August 1947. (Box 34:1677)
      - Phoenician History, 1st Essay on the. Prose No. 143. Handwritten manuscript. 16 p., February 5, 1964 (Box 34)
      - Pigeonmilk. Manuscript/typescript., 1945. (Box 34:1678)
      - Place and names. Manuscript/carbon copy., January 1962. (Box 34:1679)
      - The place, the thing, the act of the action. Typescript., 1955-1956. (Box 34:1680)
      - Plan of work. Carbon copy/Typescript., 1948. (Box 34)
      - Plans (note). Typescript., December 1963. (Box 34)
      - A plausible 'entry' for, like, man. Typescript., 1961. (Box 34)
      - A play called document. Carbon copy., 1952. (Box 34)
      - A poem is a presented duration note on poetry. Typescript/Manuscript., 1958-January 1959. (Box 34)
      - Poetry and criticism. Typescript., July 1947. (Box 34)
      - Possibilities for the Institute of the Sciences of Man, 1st draft. Prose No. 253. Typescript. 2p., [1953]
      - The post office. Carbon copy., 1948. (Box 34)
      - Post west (notes). Typescript., 1953. (Box 34)
      - Postscript to proprioception and logography. Holograph., March 1960. (Box 34)
      - Premises (notes). Holograph., October 1949. (Box 34)
      - The present state of knowledge, or, The area, and the discipline of, totality. Typescript., 1953. (Box 34)
      - The present state of romance: fragment. Typescript., November 1954. (Box 34)
      - The principle of measure in composition by field. Typescript/photocopy., December 1958-January 1959. (Box 34)
      - Problems in poetics (note). Holograph/typescript., October 1969. (Box 34)
      - Project for a book untitled. Carbon copy., 1947. (Box 34)
      - Projected verse (early draft). Photocopy of typescript., 1950. (Box 34)
      - The projective in poetry and thought and the paratactic (notes). Typescript., 1965. (Box 34)
      - Projective verse II. Typescript., 1956. (Box 34)
      - Projective verse II. Typescript., 1959. (Box 34)
      - Projective verse: early draft. Photocopy., February - July 1950. (Box 34)
      - Prose fragment. Typescript., 1932-1933. (Box 34)
      - Prose fragment. Typescript., 1952. (Box 34)
      - Pun as the true meaning as well as of rhyme. Typescript., 1964. (Box 34)
      - Quantity in verse. Typescript/holograph/photocopy., December 1958. (Box 34)
      - Quantity in verse and the late plays of Shakespeare. Typescript., December 1956. (Box 34)
      - Quantity in verse and Shakespeare's late plays. Typescript., December 1956. (Box 34)
      - Quantity in verse: Shakespeare essay. Holograph., 1954. (Box 34)
    - R-So
      - Raymond Weaver essay. Typescript/carbon copy., April 1948. (Box 35)
      - Regret. Typescript., October 1932. (Box 35)
      - Religious, racial and national origin factors. Typescript., May 1946. (Box 35)
      - The resistance. Typescript., 1949. (Box 35)
      - Respone to Richard Chase's Herman Melville. Typescript., March 1950. (Box 35)
      - A review of Eric Havelocks' Preface to Plato. Holograph/typescript., November-December 1963. (Box 35)
      - Review of John Wilmerdings' Fitz Hugh Lane. Typescript., August 1964. (Box 35)
      - Review of Robert Creeley's For Love. Typescript/holograph., 1962. (Box 35)
      - Rhapsodia to sew song together. Typescript., 1949. (Box 35)
      - The scapegoat. Photocopy of typescript., March 1950. (Box 35)
      - The science of mythology. Holograph/typescript., 1953. (Box 35)
      - The search in art, or Notes on the New Dimension (lecture notes). Holograph/carbon copy., 1948. (Box 35)
      - The secret of the black chrysanthemum. Holograph., 1969. (Box 35)
      - Session number one. Holograph/typescript., February 1953. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare chap. 10: Out this side. Typescript., December 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare chap. 7: To make cold nymphs chaste crowns. Typescript., November 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare chap. 8: The individual scene. Typescript., November 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare chap. 9: The poem unlimited. Typescript., 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare chap. VI: The new Morris. Typescript., November 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare chapter 9: the poem unlimited. Typescript., 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare essays, notes and fragments. Typescript/holograph., 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare pt II: The sedged crown. Typescript., November 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare pt III: The human title. Typescript., November 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare pt IV: The so-called masque and W. Shakespeare. Typescript., November 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare pt V: The bergomask. Typescript., November 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shakespeare pt. 1: The difference of men. Typescript., November 1954. (Box 35)
      - Shape up. Typescript/photocopy., 1953. (Box 35)
      - A short guide to present advantages. Photocopied typescript., May 1962. (Box 35)
      - Shortness of time. Typescript., March 1968. (Box 35)
      - So I am an only child. Typescript., May 1946. (Box 35)
      - Society is a diversion of attention. Typescript., December 1963. (Box 35)
      - Sophocles, or Dilemma. Typescript., 1955. (Box 35)
      - Southerners of the Civil War. Typescript., ca. 1947. (Box 35)
    - Sp-Y
      - Space and time (note). Holograph/typescript., 1947. (Box 36)
      - The spell. Holograph/typescript., 195-? (Box 36)
      - Starting where you are. Typescript., 1953. (Box 36)
      - A "state" destroys a noun. Typescript., December 1963. (Box 36)
      - Stocking cap. Typescript., 1948. (Box 36)
      - The suspense. Holograph/typescript., January 1964. (Box 36)
      - A syllabary for a dancer. Carbon copy/typescript., 1952. (Box 36)
      - A tao for here and now. Typescript., 1951. (Box 36)
      - Telepinus. Holograph/typescript., 1961. (Box 36)
      - The Tempest no tempest. Typescript., June 1954. (Box 36)
      - The terrible whaleman Samuel B. Comstock. Typescript., 1945-1946. (Box 36)
      - That flutter in the lightest wind. Holograph/typescript., May 1961. (Box 36)
      - That point at which analogies are facts of myths and science. Typescript., 1953-1956. (Box 36)
      - The theatre for Wes Huss with thanks. Typescript/photocopy., 1953. (Box 36)
      - Theatre Institute lecture on language. Holograph/photocopy., 1952. (Box 36)
      - Theatre with Wes Huss. Typescript., 1953. (Box 36)
      - Theory of society. Holograph., 1960. (Box 36)
      - There are four measurements. Typescript., January 1964. (Box 36)
      - There are four measurements. Holograph/typescript., January 1964. (Box 36)
      - This is a strange one. Typescript., November 1968. (Box 36)
      - This walking as though it were by one silk thread. Typescript., 1950. (Box 36)
      - "Though the practice of American poets since 1908..." Typescript., 1956. (Box 36)
      - The three traps. Typescript., 1953. (Box 36)
      - Time and physicality. Typescript., December 1963. (Box 36)
      - To found a science of mythology. Typescript., 1953. (Box 36)
      - To make it clear. Typescript., 1953. (Box 36)
      - "To partition reality is to lose it." Holograph., 1951. (Box 36)
      - To the writer of a new biography of Captain John Smith. Typescript., August 1964. (Box 36)
      - Troilus. Holograph/carbon copy., 1948. (Box 36)
      - Troilus: a mask. Carbon copy., 1948. (Box 36)
      - Tutorial: the Greeks. Typescript., June 1955. (Box 36)
      - Under the mushroom. Typescript., 1960-1961. (Box 36)
      - Unsticking the sun or something, perhaps for Walt Whitman. Carbon copy/photocopy., 1952. (Box 36)
      - Verse (notes). Typescript., November 1955. (Box 36)
      - The vertical ignorance. Typescript., 1958-1959. (Box 36)
      - The Vinland map review. Typescript., October 1965. (Box 36)
      - Violence is the door: notes on sex violence. Typescript., 1950. (Box 36)
      - The "voice" of perspective is wrong. Typescript., January 1964. (Box 36)
      - We are at the midpoint of the institute tonight. Typescript/holograph., March 1953. (Box 36)
      - West and the long poem. Holograph., 1948-1949. (Box 36)
      - White isle in the black sea. Holograph., January 1962. (Box 36)
      - Wild man fragment and Death and rot, a morality play. Typescript., 1961-1962. (Box 36)
      - "With some, things go to the head..." Photocopy of typescript/carbon copy., May 1952. (Box 36)
      - You can't use words as ideas. Holograph., October 1964. (Box 36)
    - Oversize E-W
      - 1st Addition... to The Animate versus the Mechanical. Prose No. 315. Holograph. 3p., April 1969 (Box 37)
      - An Essay in the Direction of a Restoration of the Act of MYTH. Prose No. 42. Holograph/typescript. 12p., ca. October 1951-1953. (Box 37)
      - "I have to confess that I am, much more than a poet, an historian..." Prose No. 158. Holograph/typescript. 24p., November 16, 1967. (Box 37)
      - A Letter to the Faculty of Black Mountain College. Prose No. 239. Photocopy/typescript. 30p. Also included, Life article "J. Robert Oppenheimer," by Lincoln Barnett. Photocopy. 15p., March 21, 1952. (Box 37)
      - The MYTHO-. Prose No. 92. Typescript. 15p., May 1955. (Box 37)
      - Notes on Language ["base texts..."]. Prose No. 41. Typescript. 11p., ca. October 1951. (Box 37)
      - The principle extrications and new coordinates now called for. Prose No. 40. Holograph/typescript. 8p., ca. September - December 1951. (Box 37)
      - Propositions. Prose No. 50. Typescript. 20p., ca. May - October 1952. (Box 37)
      - Proprioception: A Small Book. Prose No. 285. Typescript/carbon copy. 25p., ca. 1962. (Box 37)
      - Quantity in Verse and Shakespeare's Late Work. Prose No. 280. Holograph/typescript. 36p., April 1956. (Box 37)
      - A Reversal-of-Field Theory. Prose No. 93. Typescript. 14p., May 1955. (Box 37)
      - Shakespeare Essays: Notes and Fragments. Prose No. 271. Holograph/typescript. 27p., 1954. (Box 37)
      - The Special View of History Applied to the Two "Mysteries" -- of Samothrace and Eleusis. Prose No. 99. Typescript/photocopy. 22p., ca. 1956. (Box 37)
      - A Valuable Book despite the Attacks on it, and its own Staleness. Prose No. 126. Typescript/holograph. 3p., June 13, 1962. (Box 37)
      - West. Prose No. 252. Holograph. 10p., November 4, 1953. (Box 37)
  - G. Red, White and Black
    - Project notes, 1946-1948 (Box 38)
  - H. The Fiery Hunt
    - Project notes, 1946-1948 (Box 39)
  - I. Ezra Pound materials, 1946-1948
    - Notes from St. Elizabeth interviews, newspaper clippings, etc. (Box 40)
  - J. Donner Party and Gold Discovery
    - Project notes, 1947-1948, 1968 (Box 41)
    - Project notes, 1947-1948, 1968 (Box 42)
  - K. Shakespeare and the Earl of Oxford
    - Project notes, 1948 (Box 43)
  - L. Special View of History
    - Notes, 1951-1957 (Box 44)
  - M. "Equal, That Is, To the Real Itself"
    - Notes, 1958 (Box 45)
  - N. Psilocybin experiment
    - Notes, 1960-1962 (Box 46)
  - O. Dorchester records and Weymouth Port books
    - Microfilm, 1963-1967 (Box 47)
  - P. Causal Mythology
    - Transcriptions, 1965-1968 (Box 48)
  - Q. Notebooks and Diaries, 1932-1969
    - Notebook. No. 25., March 1, 1932 - March 25, 1934. (Box 49)
    - N.Y. City. No. 26., May 6, 1934 - 1936. (Box 49)
    - Journal of Swordfishing Cruise on the Doris M. Hawes, Capt. Cecil Moulton. Published in Olson: The Journal of the Charles Olson Archives 7 (Spring 1977): p.3-42. No. 27., July 1936. (Box 49)
    - Notebook. No. 28., September 1, 1936. (Box 49)
    - Key West II. Filed with a typed transcription. Portions published in Olson: The Journal of the Charles Olson Archives 5 (Spring 1976): p. 3-11. No. 57., February 1945 - April 1945. (Box 49)
    - Washington Fall 1945 I. No. 55., October 25, 1945 - December 19, 1945. (Box 49)
    - Washington, Fall 1945 II. Filed with a typed transcription. No. 31., Fall 1945 - Spring 1946. (Box 49)
    - Field Book, Enniscorthy. No. 38., Summer 1946. (Box 49)
    - Enniscorthy. Portions published in Olson: The Journal of the Charles Olson Archives 5 (Spring 1976): p. 12-13. No. 52., June 1946 - September 1946. (Box 49)
    - Verse and Geometry plus E.P., Washington. No. 37., November 1946. (Box 49)
    - Merchants of the sea. Includes poetry. No. 1., ca. 1946 - 1947. (Box 50)
    - Book. No. 39., ca. 1947. (Box 50)
    - Washington. No. 32., February 1947 - ca. May 1947. (Box 50)
    - Notebook. No. 40., February 1947 - December 2, 1947. (Box 50)
    - Myth Washington. No. 42., Spring 1947. (Box 50)
    - Giovanni di Paolo, 1403-1483. Filed with photocopy. No. 43., 1948. (Box 50)
    - Faust Buch #1, Washington. Filed with photocopy. No. 41., April 1947 - July 22, 1948. (Box 50)
    - Gonagadet. No. 33., ca. 1947 - 1949. (Box 50)
    - Notebook. No. 34., ca. April 1952 - November 1952. (Box 50)
    - Notebook. Record of dreams. No. 137., October 19, 1952 - November 12, 1955. (Box 50)
    - John White the Patriarch of Dorchester. No. 45., ca. 1953. (Box 50)
    - In the present/neither right nor left nor center. No. 59., 1953. (Box 50)
    - Camp Convention Notepad. No. 58., ca. 1953. (Box 50)
    - A Calendar of the Order of Dreams. No. 36., April 8, 1953 - September 1, 1953. (Box 50)
    - White bureau/small trunk. Includes poetry. No. 2., ca. May 15, 1954 - February 1955. (Box 50)
    - The Period. Includes notes from August 7, 1954, February 15, 1955, and March 6, 1955. No. 35., 1954 - 1955. (Box 51)
    - Notebook. No. 60., ca. 1954 - 1955. (Box 51)
    - Notebook. No. 61., ca. 1956. (Box 51)
    - III: Real Goods. No. 66., ca. 1956 - October 1957. (Box 51)
    - Olson's passport. Annotated. No. 64., 1957. (Box 51)
    - Olson's 1st large notebook. With note for October 1955. No. 135., Spring 1956 - 1957. (Box 51)
    - 58 and Brooks conv. April 59 II Cape Ann Historical maps etc. No. 65., August 1957. (Box 51)
    - I (begins after "a begin a plant"). Portions published in Olson: The Journal of the Charles Olson Archives 5 (Spring 1976): p.61-62. No. 136., September 15, 1957. (Box 51)
    - How small the news was. Includes poetry. No. 3., 1957/1958 - December 5, 1960. (Box 51)
    - Sign 1 (Charlotte). Includes poetry. No. 4., ca. 1957 - 1958. (Box 51)
    - Endicott, that year. Includes poetry. No. 6., ca. 1958. (Box 51)
    - Notepad. No. 139., 1958. (Box 51)
    - Notepad. No. 144., ca. 1958. (Box 51)
    - Don't cover anything. With notes from 1953 laid in. No. 67., ca. February 1958. (Box 51)
    - Fr P-Town. No. 81., July 1958 - February 1959. (Box 51)
    - I 1623. No. 63., February 16, 1958. (Box 51)
    - II/A long time to fill the wells. Includes poetry. No. 7., March 1958 - November 1958. (Box 51)
    - Index. No. 75., ca. Spring 1958 - 1959. (Box 52)
    - Notepad. No. 140., May 1958 - June 1958. (Box 52)
    - Notepad. No. 141., May 1958. (Box 52)
    - Dream Journal. No. 82., June 11, 1958 - July 8, 1958. (Box 52)
    - Dream Journal. No. 83., July 12, 1958 - August 26, 1958. (Box 52)
    - Gloucester - Spring 1959. No. 70., Spring 1958 - ca. September 9, 1959. (Box 52)
    - Notepad. No. 142., December 1958. (Box 52)
    - Even though the land policy of the Mass. Bay Co. ... Includes poetry. No. 44., ca. 1950 - 1959. (Box 52)
    - Notebook. No. 62., 1959. (Box 52)
    - Wm Stevens John Briar, Ralph Parker... No. 72., 1959. (Box 53)
    - Gloucester Town Records I. No. 71., ca. 1959. (Box 53)
    - Notebook. No. 69., ca. 1958 - 1959. (Box 53)
    - Notepad. No. 143., 1959. (Box 53)
    - Gloucester Feb/59. Max 1639. No. 73., ca. February 1959. (Box 53)
    - Gloucester Town Records III. Staying with Mr. White. No. 80., February 3, 1959. (Box 53)
    - Notebook. With notes dated December 16, 1969. No. 76., February 13, 1959 - October 4, 1959. (Box 53)
    - III. No. 86., August 1959 - March 1960. (Box 53)
    - I: April, 1959. Gloucester Town Records III. No. 79. (Box 53)
    - A world or life view to contest the classical-representational and confirm the primitive-abstract. No. 77., April 1, 1959 - July 19, 1959. (Box 53)
    - 2nd such book/Gloucester sources. No. 78., May 15, 1959. (Box 53)
    - On the Kings Mt. men. Includes poetry. No. 8., ca. October 1959. (Box 53)
    - Gothonic. Includes poetry. No. 5., ca. Winter 1957 - 1959. (Box 53)
    - H. Josselyn He and a John Wallis. Notepad. No. 85., ca. 1960. (Box 54)
    - D'town. No. 88., December 8, 1960 - February 21, 1961. (Box 54)
    - Indians I. No. 87., March 1960 - April 1960. (Box 54)
    - Started night of May 27th... No. 134., May 27, 1960 - July 11, 1960. (Box 54)
    - Notes July 1960? and June 1961. Removed from inside back cover of notebook (below) entitled "Gloucester Persons Book," dated 1961. No. 102., July 1960 - June 1961. (Box 54)
    - Where did Mr. John Tylly go from Gloucester... No. 89., ca. 1961. (Box 54)
    - Gloucester Persons Book. "Starts July 4th 1961." Includes notes from January 1961. Additional notebook removed from back cover, entitled "Notes July 1960? and June 1961." No. 98., ca. January 1961 on. (Box 54)
    - Geography. Psilocybin experiment with Timothy Leary and Arthur Koestler. No. 90., February 1961. (Box 54)
    - Gravelly Hill. Notepad. Includes poetry. No. 9., March 1961. (Box 54)
    - Opened March 20, 1961. Includes poetry. No. 10., March 20, 1961 - ca. August 6, 1961. (Box 54)
    - To select Lane's drawings. Notepad. Includes poetry. With note from 1 June 1962 inserted. No. 11., June 1961. (Box 54)
    - Bibliography. No. 91., September 12, 1961 - September 27, 1961. (Box 54)
    - Notepad. No. 68., ca. November 29, 1961. (Box 54)
    - ff. No. 84., ca. 1959 - 1962. (Box 55)
    - Notepad. No. 147., November 1962 - March 1963. (Box 55)
    - Out of control, ignorant. Includes poetry. No. 12., October 1962 - November 1962. (Box 55)
    - Notepad. No. 145., November 1962. (Box 55)
    - Notepad. No. 146., ca. 1962 - 1963. (Box 55)
    - Blue Book of Telephone Numbers and Area Codes. No. 101., September 23, 1963 - January 21, 1964. (Box 55)
    - Father! of Typhoeus. Includes poetry. No. 13., March 1963. (Box 55)
    - Notepad. No. 148., May 1963 -1964. (Box 55)
    - It is all rests on nothing. Includes poetry. Also includes letter draft from March 30, 1964, and "West 6" from March 4, 1964. No. 14. (Box 56)
    - Notepad. Written on "Vanity Fair" typewriter paper pad. Includes poetry. No. 15., Spring 1964. (Box 56)
    - Wyoming. No. 100., ca. June 1964. (Box 56)
    - Notepad. Begins with Olson's will. No. 99., September 3, 1964. (Box 56)
    - Notebook. No. 103., November 22, 1964 - December 13, 1964. (Box 56)
    - Book #1. Also includes notes for January 24, 1966, and March 2-4, 1966. No. 94., December 11, 1965 - January 23, 1966. (Box 56)
    - Bedroom Notebook. No. 93., December 30, 1965 - February 1966. (Box 56)
    - Death Will Have Opened Its Jaws. No. 95., May 1965 - June 1965. (Box 56)